<html>
<head>
 <title>Date class</title>
</head>
<body>
<h1><b>Date class
<br />
</b></h1>
<br />
<normal>Class <mono><b>date</b></mono><normal> is designed for working with dates. Possible variants of using it include: calendars, various checks based on dates, etc.
<br />
<br />
Values may range from 01/01/1970 to 01/01/2038.
<br />
<br />
Do not forget that we have different gaps and overlaps: many countries have so-called Daylight Saving Time, when clock is set ahead (in spring) or back (in autumn) one hour.
<br />
For example, in Moscow, there cannot be "02:00, 31 March 2002," while "02:00, 27 October 2002" can be twice.
<br />
<br />
Numeric value of object of class </normal><mono><b>date</b></mono><normal> equals to the number of days from EPOCH (00:00:00, 1 January 1970, UTC) to the date specified in the object. This feature is useful when you want to get a relative date, e.g.:
<br />
<br />
</normal><mono><monoblue><b>#&nbsp;checking&nbsp;if&nbsp;the&nbsp;file&nbsp;was&nbsp;updated&nbsp;more&nbsp;than&nbsp;a&nbsp;week&nbsp;ago
<br />
^if($last_update&nbsp;&gt;&nbsp;$now-7){
<br />
</b></monoblue></mono><mono><b>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;new
<br />
</b><monoblue><b>}{
<br />
</b></monoblue></mono><mono><b>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;old
<br />
</b><monoblue><b>}
<br />
</b></monoblue></mono><normal>
<br />
The number of days can be fractional, e.g. a day and half is equal to </normal><mono><b>1.5</b></mono><normal>.
<br />
<br />
The class usually operates local date and time. Still, you can get date and time in arbitrary time zone (see </normal><mono><b>^date</b><b>.</b><b><a href="dateroll.htm">roll</a></b><b>[TZ;&#133;]</b></mono><normal>.
<br />
<br />
To communicate between computers that are in different time zones it is convinient to exchange values of date/time which do not depend on timezone-UNIX format, which is number of seconds passed since EPOCH, is very convinient here.
<br />
<br />
Unix format can be used in JavaScript and several other scripting languages that work in browser.
<br />
<br />
Parser fully supports work with UNIX date format.
<br />
<br />
</normal></normal><br />
</body>
</html>